{"tossups": [{"question": "In one experiment, two of these animals were yoked together and given electric shocks that could be ended by pressing a lever. That experiment on these animals was conducted by Steve Maier and Martin Seligman and was used to develop learned helplessness theory. In another experiment, these animals had their esophagi cut and developed a conditioned reflex to an external stimulus. For the point, name these animals that were made to salivate by Ivan Pavlov.", "answer": "<b><u>dog</u></b>s  [Sean McBr<u>ide]</u>", "metadata": "Social Science - Social Science - Psychology"}, {"question": "A painting <em>set in this country</em> features a bare-chested man sitting in the <em>Thinker</em> pose in front of a green-clad Rogers\u2019 Ranger, anachronistically includes Simon Fraser, and controversially depicted its subjects in contemporary dress, rather than classical. Native legends from this country were used as the basis for <em>The Spirit of Haida Gwaii</em> and <em>Raven and the First Men</em> by  Bill Reid. For the point, name this country, the setting of Benjamin West\u2019s painting of <em>The Death</em> <em>of General Wolfe</em> at the Battle of Quebec.", "answer": "<b><u>Canada</u> </b> [Rob Carso<u>n]</u>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Visual Fine Arts"}, {"question": "The first ruler of this dynasty rose to power after winning the battle of Lake Poyang, and this dynasty crushed the Miao rebellions. The missionary Matteo Ricci was active during this dynasty. The last ruler of this dynasty hanged himself as the capital fell to Li Zicheng. Its capital had shifted under the Yongle ruler, who also dispatched the treasure fleets led by Zheng He. For the point, identify this dynasty that ruled China before the Manchu invasion.", "answer": "<b><u>Ming</u></b> dynasty [or Empire of the Great <b><u>Ming</u></b>; or <em><b><u>Ming</u></b> chao</em>; or <em>Da</em> <em><b><u>Ming</u></b> Di Guo</em>] [Zihan Zhen<u>g]</u>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "This city hosted a 2009 UN-sponsored international climate change conference. A paradigm in physics which opposed complementarity in describing atoms as quantum mechanical systems is known as this city\u2019s namesake \u201cinterpretation\u201d. A physicist from this city formulated the correspondence principle and first modeled a ground-state hydrogen atom as having probabilistic orbitals. For the point, name the city in which Niels Bohr worked, the capital of Denmark.", "answer": "<b><u>Copenhagen</u> </b> [Ankit Agg<u>arwal]</u>", "metadata": "Science - Physics"}, {"question": "This man gained command of an army after the consuls Hirtius and Pansa were killed at the battles of Forum Gallorum and Mutina. This ruler beat Sextus Pompeius at Naulochus and used the title <em>princeps</em>, or \u201cfirst citizen.\u201d This man\u2019s general Marcus Agrippa defeated Mark Antony at the Battle of Actium. For the point, name this adopted son of Julius Caesar who was the first emperor of Rome.", "answer": "<b><u>Augustus</u></b> Caeasar [or Imperator Caesar Divi Filius <b><u>Augustus</u></b> or Gaius Julius Caesar <b><u>Octavian</u></b>us<u>; or</u> <b><u>Gaius</u><u> Octavius</u></b>; or <b><u>Gaius Julius Caesar Divi</u> <u>Filius</u></b><u>; or</u> <b><u>Imperator Caesar</u></b> <b><u>Divi Filiu</u><u>s</u></b>]  <u>[Patrick Li</u>ao]", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {"question": "This organization resolved the Incident at Petrich and the Aland Island crisis. A Japanese-backed Racial Equality Clause failed to be included in this organization\u2019s covenant. The Permanent Court of International Justice was attached to this organization that voted itself out of existence in 1946. The covenant of this organization was enacted at the Paris Peace Conference alongside the Treaty of Versailles. For the point, name this failed predecessor of the United Nations.", "answer": "<b><u>League of Nations</u></b> [prompt on the <b><u>League</u></b>]  [Patrick Lia<u>o]</u>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "As emperor, this man began the <em>Alimenta</em> welfare program for children, and his victories over Decebalus lead to the conquest and addition of Dacia to the empire. This correspondent of Pliny the Younger launched military campaigns into Parthia that brought the Roman empire to its largest extent. When this man succeeded Nerva, he became the second of the five good emperors. For the point, a column was built in Rome by what emperor, the successor of Nerva?", "answer": "<b><u>Trajan</u> </b> [Zihan Zhen<u>g]</u>", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {"question": "In June 2014, the leader of this country introduced a fifteen point peace plan that called for a weeklong ceasefire. In this country, the key transport hub of Debaltseve was recently taken over by separatist fighters. The Minsk Protocol was meant to stop the war in this country, but fighting has continued in the Donbass region. In 2014, Russia annexed the Crimean peninsula from this country. For the point, name this Eastern European country currently experiencing a civil war, whose capital is Kiev.", "answer": "<b><u>Ukraine</u> </b> [Tejas Raje]", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {"question": "One album by this man featured \u201cInner City Blues\u201d and a song that decried \u201coil wasted on the oceans.\u201d That hit song was \u201cMercy Mercy Me,\u201d which appeared on his album <em>What\u2019s Going On</em>. A recent hit pop song plagiarized this singer\u2019s \u201cGot to Give It Up,\u201d and this man sang \u201cI\u2019m just  about to lose my mind\u201d in his most famous song. For the point, name this American soul singer who was ripped off by Robin Thicke and who recorded songs like \u201cI Heard It Through the  Grapevine.\u201d", "answer": "Marvin Pentz <b><u>Gay</u></b>e Jr. [Isaac Hirsch]", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {"question": "This ruler signed the Treaty of Altmark with his cousin Sigismund III, ending his country\u2019s war with Poland. As a commander, this man was noted for his use of mobile artillery and combined arms, which he used to win the Battle of Breitenfeld. This man ruled with the support  of Axel Oxenstierna, who served as regent for his daughter Christina after this king\u2019s death at the  Battle of Lutzen. For the point, name this \u201cLion of the North\u201d, the Swedish king during the start of the Thirty Years War.", "answer": "<b><u>Gustavus Adolphus</u></b> [or <b><u>Gustav II</u></b> Adolf; accept <b><u>Sigismund III</u></b> before mention] [Tejas Raje]", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "One revolt during this period was ended at the Third Battle of Uji and its leader, Go-Toba, was exiled to the Oki Islands. The Northern and Southern Courts were started during this period, which was dominated by the <em>shikken</em> regents from the Hojo clan. The Kemmu Restoration ended this period that began after the Taira lost to the Minamoto, who set up a <em>bakufu</em> government in a namesake capital. For the point, name this period following the Heian, the first Japanese shogunate.", "answer": "<b><u>Kamakura</u></b> Shogunate [or <em><b><u>Kamakura</u></b> jidai</em>; or <em><b><u>Kamakura</u></b>bakufu</em>] [Patrick Lia<u>o]</u>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "During this battle, an ill-advised advance to the Emmitsburg Road was ordered by General Dan Sickles. For part of its first day, Union forces were led by Abner Doubleday. The order of  \u201cfix bayonets\u201d was given at this battle by Joshua Chamberlain when his forces ran out of ammunition defending Little Round Top. At the end of this battle, Winfield Scott Hancock defeated a last-ditch attack led by George Pickett. For the point, name this 1863 defeat of Robert E. Lee in Pennsylvania.", "answer": "Battle of <b><u>Gettysburg</u> </b> [Bruce Arthur]", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "The Royal Newfoundland Regiment was nearly wiped out during this battle in which the South African Brigade fought at Delville Wood. This battle was planned during the Chantilly Conference, and the lack of High Explosive shells led to most of the barbed wire remaining uncut on the first day. One engagement during this battle at Flers-Courcelette included the first combat use of tanks. For the point, name this bloody 1916 battle fought primarily by the British to relieve the French at Verdun.", "answer": "Battle of the <b><u>Somme</u></b> [or the <b><u>Somme</u></b> Offensive]  [Patrick Liao]", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "A speech given at this event included lines borrowed from Kenneth Galbraith that declared,  \u201cLet us never negotiate out of fear. But let us never fear to negotiate.\u201d Glare at this event prevented a man from reading \u201cDedication,\u201d so instead that man, Robert Frost, recited \u201cThe Gift  Outright.\u201d This event\u2019s address also included the lines \u201cAsk not what your country can do for you, ask what you can do for your country.\u201d For the point, name this event, the swearing in of the 35th President in 1961.", "answer": "<b><u>inauguration</u></b> of John F <b><u>Kennedy</u></b> or <b><u>JFK</u> </b> [Isaac Hirsc<u>h]</u>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "One group in this country had a city at Tollan and claimed to have migrated from Aztlan.  One archeological site in this country contained a \u201cwell\u201d called the Sacred Cenote, where adherents prayed to the rain god Chac. Another archaeological site in this country contains the Avenue of the Dead, the Temple of the Sun, and the Temple of the Moon. For the point, name this country which contains the Mayan ruins of Palenque and Chichen Itza and the Aztec ruins of Tenochtitlan.", "answer": "<b><u>Mexico</u> </b> [Douglas G<u>raebner]</u>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "Shortly before this battle, Commander \u201cBull\u201d Halsey was hospitalized with dermatitis and replaced by Raymond Spruance. An attempted feint at the Aleutians before this battle failed. The Hiryu was sunk in this battle, which saw extensive use of Dauntless dive bombers. The main American loss was the Yorktown, which sank after being torpedoed by a submarine. For the point, name this June 1942 naval battle, the turning point in the Pacific theater of World War II.", "answer": "Battle of <b><u>Midway</u> </b> [Jason Zhou]", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "In this nation, the 30 September Movement assassinated several generals in a coup attempt, leading to the massacre of the PKI party. \u201cPolice actions\u201d were undertaken in this nation by the Dutch. The New Order succeeded Guided Democracy in this nation, which hosted the Bandung Conference and temporarily withdrew from the UN under the leadership of Sukarno. For the point, identify this nation ruled by the military under Suharto until his fall in 1998.", "answer": "Republic of <b><u>Indonesia</u> </b> [Zihan Zheng]", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "Thomas Fitzsimmons was one of the two members of this group who signed the U.S. Constitution. During the American Revolution, the most powerful members of this group were the Carroll family. In one colony, these people lost their political rights after Coode\u2019s Rebellion overthrew the Lord Proprietor. Other members of this group included George and Cecil Calvert. For the point, name this religious group that included the founders of Maryland, Christians who recognize the authority of the Pope.", "answer": "Roman <b><u>Catholics</u></b> [or <b><u>Papists</u></b>]  [Bruce Arthur]", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This man is thought to be the author of the unsigned poem \u201cThe Suicide\u2019s Soliloquy\u201d. He is described \u201cpacing up and down\u201d near \u201cthe old court-house\u201d in a poem by Vachel Lindsay. A poem about this man describes how a \u201cgreat star early droop\u2019d in the western sky at night\u201d. He is the dedicatee of a poem whose title figure lies \u201con the deck\u201d, \u201cfallen cold and dead\u201d. Walt Whitman\u2019s elegies \u201cWhen Lilacs Last in the Dooryard Bloom\u2019d\u201d and \u201cO Captain! My Captain!\u201d are about, for the point, which American president?", "answer": "Abraham <b><u>Lincoln</u> </b> [Rob Carson]", "metadata": "Literature - American Literature - Poetry"}, {"question": "This political party was supported by the <em>Albany Evening Journal</em>, which was founded by  Thurlow Weed. Amos Ellmaker was this party\u2019s Vice Presidential nominee. William Palmer, a member of this party, was elected governor of Vermont. This party\u2019s formation was sparked by the disappearance of William Morgan and nominated William Wirt at America\u2019s first-ever political convention. For the point, name this American political party that opposed secret societies.", "answer": "<b><u>Anti-Mason</u></b>ic Party  [Bruce Arth<u>ur]</u>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "This woman was imprisoned in the Tower of London after the rebellion of Thomas Wyatt, and Anthony Babington later attempted to assassinate her. As queen, her advisors included William Cecil and Francis Walsingham. This queen executed Mary, Queen of Scots, succeeded  her sister, \u201cBloody Mary,\u201d and faced the Spanish Armada. For the point, name this daughter of Henry VIII, who reigned as the \u201cVirgin Queen.\u201d", "answer": "<b><u>Elizabeth I</u> </b> [Saul Hanki<u>n]</u>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "At his inaugural mass, this pope repeated the words \u201cBe not afraid!\u201d This author of <em>Love and</em> <em>Responsibility</em> was shot by a member of the Turkish Grey Wolves named Mehmet Ali Agca. He adopted the same papal name as his predecessor, who had only been in office for 33 days before dying in 1978. On a trip to his homeland, he spoke in favor of the Solidarity movement. For the point, name this first Polish pope, who was succeeded by Benedict XVI.", "answer": "Pope Saint <b><u>John Paul II</u></b> [or <b><u>Johannes Paulus II</u></b> or Karol J\u00f3zef <b><u>Wojty\u0142a</u></b> (voy-TIH-wah)]  [Saul Hankin]", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "This president signed the Family and Medical Leave Act into law. His administration  oversaw the introduction of the Don\u2019t Ask Don\u2019t Tell Policy in the United States military. The US suspended its separate trade agreements with Canada and Mexico and entered NAFTA during his presidency. He defeated Bob Dole and George H.W. Bush to earn his two terms. For the point, name this president whose reputation was marred by the Monica Lewinsky scandal.", "answer": "William Jefferson \u201cBill\u201d <b><u>Clinton</u> </b> [Evan Adams]", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This man\u2019s <em>Mass for Troubled Times</em> coincidentally premiered shortly after news of the Battle of the Nile reached Europe, giving it the nickname <em>Nelson Mass</em>. He wrote the melody for an anthem to Francis II that was later used as the tune for the <em>Deutschlandlied</em>. He spent much of  his career as a court musician for the Esterhazy family, and was known as the \u201cfather\u201d of both the string quartet and the symphony. For the point, name this composer of the oratorios <em>The</em> <em>Seasons</em> and <em>The Creation</em>.", "answer": "Joseph <b><u>Haydn</u></b> [or Franz Joseph <b><u>Haydn</u></b>]  [Rob Carson]", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Auditory Fine Arts"}, {"question": "This president was inaugurated in a replica of George Washington\u2019s first inauguration in  New York City. This president collaborated with the \u201cbillion dollar Congress\u201dto produce the McKinley Tariff and the Sherman Anti-Trust Act. This Republican owed his election to the Murchison Letter, which falsely claimed the British backed his opponent. For the point, name this president who served between Grover Cleveland and Grover Cleveland.", "answer": "<b><u>B</u></b>enjamin <b><u>Harrison</u></b> [prompt on <b><u>Harrison</u></b>]  [Bruce Arth<u>u</u>r]", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "One speech by this man attacked the \u201c[transformation] into a superman with supernatural characteristics\u201d. This leader carried out the Virgin Lands campaign to increase agricultural productivity. In an appearance at the United Nations, this leader banged his shoe on the table to emphasize his point. He denounced the cult of personality of his predecessor in the \u201csecret speech\u201d. For the point, name this Soviet premier during the Cuban Missile Crisis, who succeeded Stalin.", "answer": "Nikita <b><u>Khrushchev</u> </b> [Ryan Rosenberg]", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "One athlete with this nickname won the US Open while carrying a colostomy bag due to a recurrence of cancer and, earlier, won gold medals in the hurdles and javelin at the 1932 Olympics. Another athlete with this nickname was a part of \u201cMurderers Row\u201d when he broke his own single-season home run record. That man was sold by Harry Frazee in 1920, spawning his namesake \u201ccurse\u201d on the Red Sox. For the point, give this nickname shared by golfer Mildred Didrikson Zaharias and slugging Yankee Hall of Famer George Herman Ruth.", "answer": "\u201c<b><u>Babe</u></b>\u201d [Dan Passner<u>]</u>", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {"question": "This island was conquered by Roger I, and his son Roger II made it the leading maritime power in the Mediterranean. Its odd cultural mix came from its conquests by the Arab Aghlabids and the Norman de Hautevilles. Locals in this region rebelled against Charles of Anjou\u2019s rule  during its namesake \u201cVespers.\u201d For the point, name this Mediterranean island whose capital is  Palermo and which is located just off the \u201ctoe\u201d of the Italian peninsula.", "answer": "<b><u>Sicily</u> </b> [Tejas Raje]", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "A memorial commemorating this event includes a pair of twin bronze gates and a field of 168 empty chairs. In the aftermath of this event, a photograph of a firefighter holding a dying infant won a Pulitzer Prize. The perpetrators of this event, who claimed to be motivated by the standoffs at Ruby Ridge and Waco, used a fertilizer bomb and targeted the Alfred P. Murrah Federal Building. For the point, name this bombing carried out by Terry Nichols and Timothy McVeigh.", "answer": "<b><u>Oklahoma City bombing</u></b> [accept obvious synonyms and equivalents] [Evan Adam<u>s]</u>", "metadata": "History - American History"}], "bonuses": []}